So I came to CMU as a writing major.
I decided to look into the education program once I stepped foot into a school and saw someone teaching English to these kids.
I think I immediately knew that it was something that I wanted to do.
The Center for Teacher Education is a professional program.
We have several accredited programs and in broad terms that would be elementary, secondary, K through 12.
We also have an elementary program that is fully online.
When our students graduate, they are eligible to apply for a teaching license with the state of Colorado.
My favorite experience of the whole teacher program has been CMU's ability to get you into classrooms in District 51.
And what's really cool about CMU is that they let you do your observations in a lot of different schools.
I've been in a fifth grade classroom.
I've been in the first grade classroom.
Actually getting to teach has been pretty incredible.
Our program is small enough that you're going to build good relationships with faculty and with your peers.
A lot of our classes, like towards the end before internships, were really fun because we were actually practicing things that you would do with the kids.
But I really do think most of the professors care about you outside of the classroom, and they really do care about you as a person.
Being available even outside of office hours.
A lot of the support comes from their experience as grade school teachers.
They bring that knowledge into your college class by sharing their own personal experiences and saying this is what I did and kind of introducing you to new ideas.
Teachers are needed everywhere, and teachers have such a valuable role in society.
It's awesome knowing that I really could go to New York or I could go to California and most likely find a teaching job.
We have graduates who teach in Arizona, Texas, California, Wyoming, Montana.
With that Colorado license, there's a pathway that's a little bit easier to get that license in another state.
So with all of our programs, we partner with other departments across campus.
That also means that all of our candidates are going to have two advisors here.
An advisor in their concentration area, and they're going to have an advisor in education.
They really make it clear through your teaching experience before you graduate that you are always supported.
I feel ready right now because I've been in the classroom and I've been around the kids.
But I've always felt ready because they have gave me the resources and the skills that I know that I need.